Guide to the Karl Owen Thompson Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Karl Owen Thompson collection
1828-1932
MS 1217
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
A collection of approximately one hundred letters relating to Yale University. Included are letters by five Yale presidents, Yale faculty members, and letters received by George E. Day of the Divinity School. Also an essay in Latin written in 1859 by A. W. Van Hengel.
Thompson, Karl Owen, 1881-1958
Scope and Contents
The Karl Owen Thompson Collection contains a small selection of approximately one hundred letters relating to Yale University. Included are letters by five Yale presidents, Yale faculty members, and faculty members of the Divinity School, as well as letters received by George E. Day of the Divinity School. There are also letters of recommendation and other correspondence of Yale interest. The only items in the collection which are not correspondence are the 1859 passport of George E. Day and a memoir written by Professor A. W. Van Hengel of the University of Leyden in 1859.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Day, George Edward, 1815-1905; Van Hengel, A. W.; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- History; Yale University. Divinity School
- Yale University Presidents
  - Angell, James R., 1928 October 1929 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dwight, Timothy
    - Outgoing letters, 1873-1878 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Signatures, 1879, 1884, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Incoming letters, 1891-1892 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hadley, Arthur. T., 1916 December 16 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Porter, Noah, 1872-1873, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Woolsey, Theodore D., 1867, 1871, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Yale University faculty
  - Adams, George B., 1892, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Anderson, William G., 1914 May 15 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Beers, Henry Augustin (signature), undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chittenden, Russell H., 1923 April 16, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Day, Clive, 1905 October 24 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Embree, Edwin R., 1915 May 6 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Hopkins, E.W. (signature), undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ladd, George T.
    General
    see: box 1, folder 3
  - Richards, C.B., 1904 April 30 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Scott, Charles F., 1929 October 14 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Sumner, William Graham (signature), undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Swann, W.F.G., 1927 March 5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Warren, Charles H., 1924 November 14 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Divinity School faculty
  - Bailey, William B., undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Beach, Harlan P., undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Brown, Charles R., 1915 April 8 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Curtis, Edward L., 1906 February 13 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Fisher, George P., 1867 October 15 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Gilman, Daniel. C.
    see: box 1, folder 5
  - Kent, Charles F., 1924 September 23 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sanders, Frank K. (signatures), undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Stevens, George B., 1904 July 9 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Taylor, Nathaniel W., 1833 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Walker, Williston, 1905, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Weigle, Luther A., 1932 April 22 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Circular letter signed by:, undated
    - S.B. Treat (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - A.C. Thompson (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - A.S. Stone (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Jos. L. Clark (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - S.H. Higgins (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Christopher Marsh (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - F. Laurie (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Wm. C. Foster (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Rufus Anderson (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - J.L. Taylor (Box 1, Folder 6)
- George E. Day
  - Letters from:
    - Andrews, W., 1858 October 23 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bacon, Leonard W., 1862, 1867 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ballantine, W.G., 1888 June 26 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bliss, J.G., 1866 September 12 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - DeForest, J.H., 1877 December 19 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Eells, Cushing, 1888 June 16 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ely, William D., 1891 September 29 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Gilman, Daniel C., 1867 March 21 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Gunsaulus, F.W., 1886, September 20 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Harris, Samuel, 1891 July 24 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Hoppins, Jos. M., undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Laurence, Amos, 1851 July 15 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Lawrence, Edward A., undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Paine, Levi L., 1891 April 15 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Park; Edwards A., 1867 May 14 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Perrine, Enoch, 1891 June5 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Petrie, F., 1888 June 12 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Smith, Henry, 1867 November 8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Treat, S.B., 1867 November (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Signatures, 1861, 1891, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Harris, Samuel, signature, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Park, Edwards A., signature, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Passport, signed by Lewis Cass, 1859 April 9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Letters of recommendation and. other impersonal communications of Yale interest
  - Bethune, George W., undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Brickham, M.H., 1891 August 8 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Briggs, C.A., 1882 October 2 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dwight, S.E., 1834 September 36 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Edwards, B.B., 1851 July 5 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Edwards, Justin, 1836 October 29 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Fairchild, James H., 1873 August 29 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Hitchcock, Roswell D., 1870, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hodge, C.W., 1867 February 4 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hoyt, Arthur S., 1891 September 3 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Johnson, B.W., 1891 August 22 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - King, Henry C., 1887 August 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Kephart, E.B., 1894 April 20 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - MacVicar, Peter, 1883 September 3 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Mercer, E.C., 1911 June 6 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Miller, Samuel, 1836 August 12 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Moffat, J.D., 1892 September 12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Morris, E.D. (signatures), 1887 September 11 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Pond, Enoch, 1835 September 9 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Porter, E., 1828 August 4 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Raymond, B.P., 1892 July 29 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Richards, William R., 1892 October 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Schaff, Philip, 1867 October 18 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Thomas, J., 1887 July 25 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Vahl, J., 1889 October 24 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Van Hengel, A.W.: Memoir in Latin written by him in Leyden, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 13)